Guide to the Raymond C. Battalio and John B. Van Huyck Papers, 1949-2014, bulk 1972-2014 RL.11714
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Raymond C. Battalio and John B. Van Huyck papers
1949-2014, bulk dates 1972-2014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Battalio, Raymond Charles
Van Huyck, John B.
RL.11714
90 Linear Feet 66 record cartons and 15 electronic records boxes.
56.2 Gigabytes 10 sets.
Raymond C. Battalio (1938-2004) and John B. Van Huyck (1956-2014) worked together as professors of economics at Texas A&M University. This collection primarily documents their professional lives through their correspondence, writings, research (especially experiments), and professional and faculty activities. It was acquired as part of the Economists' Papers Archive.
Conditions Governing Access
Access note. Some materials in this collection are fragile audio formats that may need to be reformatted before use. Contact Research Services for access.
Conditions Governing Access
Access note. Some materials in this collection are electronic records that require special equipment. Contact Research Services with questions.
Conditions Governing Access
Access restricted. Some materials in this collection are personnel records. Records pertaining to employment where individuals are identified are closed for 70 years.
Conditions Governing Access
Access restricted. Some electronic files in RL11714-SET-0008 contain personally identifiable information (PII) that has not been redacted. Contact Research Services for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Raymond C. Battalio and John B. Van Huyck papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book and Manuscript Library as gifts in 2016.
Arrangement
The Raymond C. Battalio and John B. Van Huyck papers are arranged into six series: Correspondence, Conferences and Consulting, Writings, Research and Notes, Experiments, and Academia.
Biographical / Historical
Raymond C. Battalio (1938-2004) and John B. Van Huyck (1956-2014) were both white American academic economists who spent their entire careers at Texas A&M University (TAMU; 1969-2004 and 1984-2014, respectively).
Battalio earned a BS in economics from the University of California, Berkeley in 1966 and a MS and PhD from Purdue University in 1968 and 1970, respectively, where he was supervised by Robert Basmann. He was one of the 12 founders of the Economic Science Association (ESA) in 1986 and served as its third president from 1988-1989, and he and Van Huyck founded the Economic Research Laboratory in 1997. He was married to Nancy Battalio, had three sons (Robert, Joe, and Eric Battalio), and was a US Navy veteran.
Van Huyck was the Rex B. Grey Professor of Economics at TAMU. He earned a BA in economics from the University of Virginia in 1979 and an MA and PhD from Brown University in 1982 and 1986, respectively, where he was supervised by Herschel Grossman. He was also active in the ESA and served as a board member. He was married to Patsy Johnson, had three sons (Carl Phillips, Don Ashfield, and Bjorn Bennett Van Huyck), and was a Cub Scout den leader.
Battalio began designing experiments in the 1970s to test consumer demand theory in token economies with John Kagel, and he also studied individual choice behavior in pigeons, rats, and humans; this work had broad appeal and was widely published in economics and psychology journals.
Van Huyck's early work was on sovereign debt and macroeconomics with Herschel Grossman, and it led him to develop an interest in coordination failures and studying these specifically through experiments with Battalio.
They are primarily known for their lab work on the problem of multiple equilibria in game theory. Along with Richard Biel, they carried out a series of experiments on coordination that began with the minimum-effort coordination game in 1990. Among their other experiments were ones on the emergence of conventions, chaotic dynamics, decentralized allocation, and average opinion and peasant-dictator games.
Related Materials
Alvin Roth papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Vernon L. Smith papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Witness Seminar on Experimental Economics records, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Scope and Contents
The Raymond C. Battalio and John B. Van Huyck papers document their careers as economists at Texas A&M University (TAMU), particularly their work developing the field of experimental economics in the 1990s. Their papers are combined in one collection given their close working relationship.
The primary subjects are behavioral game theory, experimental economics, and macroeconomics. There are records related to Battalio's presidency of the Economic Science Association, Van Huyck's activity for Experimental Economics, and the founding of the Economic Research Lab at TAMU.
The most common type of material by far is research files on experiments, but there are also many correspondence files, manuscript files for writings and referee reports, course files for teaching, and files for their professional activities as economists. To a lesser extent, there are university and department files for their activities as faculty members, plus personal files from Van Huyck (especially academic coursework and family material).
The greatest amount of professional correspondence is with Charles Holt, David Levine, Thomas Palfrey, Charles Plott, Alvin Roth, and Larry Samuelson. Battalio and Van Huyck communicated with many contributors to experimental economics, and there is a lesser amount of correspondence with James Andreoni, Colin Camerer, John Kagel, and Vernon Smith.
This collection contains 1,309 floppy disks, 245 optical disks, six hard drives, five quarter-inch cartridges, and three USB thumb drives. Most or all of them belonged to Van Huyck, and he migrated files and folders to newer storage mediums over time and created backups for security or home use. Electronic records from most of these items have been copied to a server and are available. 137 installation disks for software were retained (but not copied) for possible emulation in the future; a separate inventory of them is available by request from Research Services.
Audiocassettes; Economics -- Psychological aspects; Economists -- United States -- Correspondence; Electronic records; Experimental economics; Game theory; Game theory -- Computer programs; Machine-readable artifacts; Microeconomics; Noncooperative games (Mathematics); Battalio, Raymond Charles; Economic Science Association; Economists' Papers Archive; Holt, Charles A., 1948-; Levine, David K.; Palfrey, Thomas R., 1953-; Plott, Charles R.; Roth, Alvin E., 1951-; Samuelson, Larry, 1953-; Texas A & M University. Department of Economics -- Faculty; Van Huyck, John B.
- Correspondence, 1983-2009; 1
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access restricted. Some materials are personnel records. Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
  Access note. Some materials are electronic records that require special equipment. Contact Research Services with questions.
  Access note. Some materials are fragile audio formats that may need to be reformatted before use. Contact Research Services for access.
  Scope and Contents
  Battalio and Van Huyck's correspondence, which is mainly professional in nature and with other economists, especially Charles Holt, David Levine, Thomas Palfrey, Charles Plott, Alvin Roth, and Larry Samuelson. Topics include the exchange of papers and research material, referee activity, and paper submissions. Organized into three subseries to preserve their original order: Alphabetical Correspondence (for Van Huyck), Chronological Correspondence (for Battalio), and Email Correspondence (from Van Huyck's computer disk drives).
  - Alphabetical Correspondence, 1983-2006; 1
    Van Huyck's correspondence, sometimes on behalf of himself and Battalio and almost entirely professional. Topics include the exchange of papers and research material, referee activity, paper submissions, and job searches and offers, and the largest amount is with Larry Samuelson. Arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent or organization/institution.
    - Abreu, Dilip, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - Al-Najjar, Nabil, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Alesina, A., 1985-1993 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Beth, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Alm, James, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Alphabetical Correspondence Electronic Files, 1994-1996; 596 files; approximately 3 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0001)
      Text files.
    - Altig, Dave, 1985-1993 (Box 1)
    - Amershi, Amin H., 1989 (Box 1)
    - Andreoni, James, 1993-2002 (Box 1)
    - Arthur, W. Brian, 1989-1992 (Box 1)
    - Ashenfelter, Orley, 1986-1996 (Box 1)
    - Bacharach, Michael, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Ball, Sheryl, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Baltagi, Badi, undated (Box 1)
    - Barro, Robert, 1988-1993 (Box 1)
    - Barton, C.J., 1987 (Box 1)
    - Battalio, Ray, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
      Brief correspondence about writing and research experiments during Van Huyck's time at UC San Diego.
    - Battalio, Ray, 1994 (Box 14)
      Related to Hawk-Dove and Asset Market experiments, among others.
    - Battalio, Ray Electronic Files, 1988; 4 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0001, Box 77, Disk RL11714-FL5-0070)
    - Baye, Mike, 1986-1991 (Box 1)
    - Beckman, Steve, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Beil, Richard, 1990-1994 (Box 1)
    - Bell, Clive, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Ben-David, S., 1986 (Box 1)
    - Benjamin, A.T., 1992 (Box 1)
    - Bernheim, D., 1986 (Box 1)
    - Berthold, N., undated (Box 1)
    - Binmore, Ken, 1989-1994 (Box 1)
      About exchanging papers and a planned visit by Van Huyck.
    - Blanchard, Olivier J., 1985 (Box 1)
    - Bohn, Henning, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
    - Bolton, Gary, 1992-1995 (Box 1)
    - Boschen, John, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Boylan, R., 1988 (Box 1)
    - Brada, Josef, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Brandenburger, Adam, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Brandts, Jordi, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Bray, M., 1995 (Box 1)
    - Bronars, Steve, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Bronfman, Corinne, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Broseta, Bruno, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Brunner, K., 1985 (Box 1)
    - Bryant, John, 1988-1996 (Box 1)
      About exchanging papers and other routine matters.
    - Cabrales, Antonio, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
    - California Institute of Technology: Package Sent, 1995 (Box 14)
      About exchanging research material.
    - California Institute of Technology Electronic Files, 1992-1995; 24 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0001, Box 75, Disk RL11714-FL3-1172)
      Text and executable files.
    - Camerer, Colin, 1990-1995 (Box 1)
    - Camerer and Weber: Data Request (ESL1), 1995 (Box 14)
    - Camerer and Weber Electronic Files, 1992-1995; 28 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0001, Box 75, Disk RL11714-FL3-1170)
    - Campbell, Joseph, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Canova, Fabio, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Canzoneri, Matt, 1988-1993 (Box 1)
    - Carlsson, Hans: Papers Sent, 1995 (Box 14)
    - Carlsson, Hans Electronic Files, 1990-1995; 4 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0001, Box 75, Disk RL11714-FL3-1171)
      Text files; zipped folder.
    - Cason, Tim, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Caves, Richard, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Chen, Ping, 1989-1992 (Box 1)
    - Cho, In-Koo, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Chokley, Nancy, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Cole, Harold, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Conlisk, John, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Cooper, David, 1994-1996 (Box 1)
    - Cook, Joe, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Cooper, R., 1987-1994 (Box 1)
    - Original Microcassette, Correspondence, Tape 1, undated (Box 79, Audio-cassette RL11714-MCS-0002)
    - Cosimano, Tom, 1987-1993 (Box 1)
    - Cox, James C., 1988 (Box 1)
    - Crawford, Vince, 1985-1994 (Box 1)
    - Cronk, Lee, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Cullison, William, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Cukierman, Alex, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Dartmouth College, 1986 (Box 1)
      Personal correspondence about job search.
    - David, Paul, 1989-1992 (Box 1)
    - Davis, Steve, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
    - Day, Richard, 1991-1996 (Box 1)
    - DeJong, Doug, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Del Villar, Rafael, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Diamantaras, Dimitrios, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Diba, Behzad, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Dickhaut, John, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Dotsey, Michael, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Drees, Burkhard, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Driffill, John, 1986-1992 (Box 1)
    - Driskill, Robert, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Duffy, John, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Eckel, Katherine, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Echienbaum, M., 1986 (Box 1)
    - Eichengreen, Barry J., 1993 (Box 1)
    - Eisner, Robert, 1988 (Box 1)
    - El-Gamal, Mahmoud, 1992-1994 (Box 1)
    - Epple, Dennis, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Erev, Ido, 1993-1998 (Box 1)
    - Evans, Paul, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Farmer, Roger, 1987-1994 (Box 1)
    - Fehr, Ernst, 2006 (Box 14)
    - Fischer, Stanley, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Forsythe, Robert, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
    - Foss Davis, Kirsten, 1985-1989 (Box 1)
    - Friedman, Benjamin, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - Friedman, Daniel, 1992-1994 (Box 1)
    - Friedman, James, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Frydman, Roman, 1984-1989 (Box 1)
    - Fundenberg, Drew, 1990-2000 (Box 1)
    - Garber, Peter, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Garfinkel, Michelle, 1988-1993 (Box 1)
    - George Washington University, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Gibbons, Robert, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Gillette, Ann, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Goodfriend, Marvin, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Green, Steve, 1986-1995 (Box 1)
    - Grossman, Herschel, 1983-1995 (Box 1)
      About exchanging papers, publication of research, and research funding.
    - Guler, Kamal, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Haley, David W., 1991 (Box 1)
    - Hall, Bob, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Haller, Hans, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Haltwanger, J., 1987-1989 (Box 1)
    - Haslag, Joseph, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Haraf, Bill, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Harrison, Glen, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Harsanyi, John, 1988-1992 (Box 1)
      About exchanging papers.
    - Haveman, Robert H., 1990-1991 (Box 1)
    - Hayford, Marc, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Heckman, James, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Heiner, Ronald, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Hellwig, Martin, 1989-1991 (Box 1)
      About Econometrica.
    - Hey, John D., 1994-1996 (Box 1)
    - Hirshleifer, Jack, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Hoffman, Elizabeth, 1989-1996 (Box 1)
    - Holt, Charles, 1992-2004 (Box 1)
    - Hosek, James, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Hoshi, Takeo, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Huck, Steffan, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Isaac, Mark, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Jackson, P.M., 1989 (Box 1)
    - Jadlow, Joseph M., 1992 (Box 1)
    - Jeong, Jin-Ho, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Jewitt, Ian, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
    - Job Search, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
    - John, Andrew, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Johnson, William R., 1992 (Box 1)
    - Journal of Development Economics, 1997 (Box 1)
      About referee request.
    - Journal of Monetary Economics, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
    - Kagel, John, 1988-1992 (Box 1)
    - Kahn, Larry, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
    - Kalai, Ehud, 1990-2000 (Box 1)
      About Games and Economic Behavior.
    - Kansas City Fed, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Kehoe, Patrick, 1988-1993 (Box 1)
    - Keser, Claudia, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Kim, Yong-Gwan, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
    - Kim, Yongse, 1993 (Box 1)
    - King, Robert, 1987-1989 (Box 1)
    - Klein, Dan, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Kohlberg, Elon, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Kreps, David, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Kydland, Finn, 1986-1993 (Box 1)
    - Laing, James, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Lau, Sau-Him Paul, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Ledyard, John, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
    - Levin, Dan, 1989-2005 (Box 1)
    - Levine, David, 1990-2001 (Box 1)
      About Econometric Society.
    - Levine, Paul, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Lindert, Peter H., 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    - LItterman, R., 1986 (Box 1)
    - Lott, John, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Longawa, Vicky, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Marimon, Ramon, 1990-1992 (Box 1)
    - Marks, Robert, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Marx, Leslie M., 1993-1994 (Box 1)
    - Maskin, Eric, 1988-1991 (Box 1)
      About refereeing.
    - Matsuyama, Kiminori, 1988 (Box 1)
    - McAfee, Preston, 1993-1997 (Box 1)
      About American Economic Review.
    - McAllister, Patrick, 1993 (Box 1)
    - McCabe, Kevin, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
    - McCafferty, Stephen, 1986-1995 (Box 2)
    - McCallum, Bennett, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
    - McCulloch, J. Houston, 1988 (Box 2)
    - McGratten, Ellen, 1989 (Box 2)
    - McKelvey, Richard, 1992-1997 (Box 2)
    - Meltzer, A.H., 1985-1990 (Box 2)
    - Menezes, Flavio, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Merlo, Antonio, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Mertens, Jean-Francois, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Meyer, Don, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Milgrom, Paul, 1989-1992 (Box 2)
    - Mirowski, Phillip, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Morton, Peter, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Motomura, Akira, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Nam, Il Chong, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Neilson, W.S., 1991 (Box 2)
    - Neral, John, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Nordhaus, W., 1986 (Box 2)
    - North, Douglas C., 1992-1993 (Box 2)
    - North, Susan, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Nyarko, Yaw, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Oaxaca, Ronald L., 1988 (Box 2)
    - Ochs, Jack, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
    - O'Connell, Steve, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Oh, Seonghwan, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Oh, Young Rhan, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Olsen, E.O., 1994 (Box 2)
    - Olson, Mark, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Ortmann, Adreas, 1991-1994 (Box 2)
    - Page, Frank, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Palfrey, Thomas, 1991-1996 (Box 2)
    - Papers I Requested: No Response, 1989 (Box 2)
      Unanswered requests for papers by Van Huyck from authors.
    - Papers I Requested: Responded, 1983-1990 (Box 2)
      Answered requests for papers by Van Huyck from authors.
    - Papers Requested: Others, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
      Requests received by Van Huyck for copies of papers.
    - Paquet, Alain, 1988-1990 (Box 2)
    - Pearce, David, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Pechman, Joseph A., 1987-1988 (Box 2)
    - Peltzman, Sam, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Persson, Torsten, 1989-1993 (Box 2)
    - Philadelphia Fed, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Piterman, Sylvia, undated (Box 2)
    - Plosser, Charles I., 1986-1987 (Box 2)
      About publishing in Journal of Monetary Economics.
    - Quah, D., 1987 (Box 2)
    - Ramey, Garey, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Rapoport, Amnon, 1988-1992 (Box 2)
    - Rasmussen, Eric, 1989-1993 (Box 2)
    - Rassentos, Stephen, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Riordan, Michael H., 1991 (Box 2)
      About refereeing for RAND Journal.
    - Roberds, Will, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Roberds, William, 1987 (Box 14)
    - Roberts, Kevin, 1986 (Box 2)
      About submission to Review of Economic Studies.
    - Rogers, Carol Ann, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Rogerson, Richard, undated (Box 2)
    - Rogoff, K., 1986-1993 (Box 2)
    - Rolnik, Zachary, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Root, Hilton, undated (Box 2)
    - Romer, C., 1985 (Box 2)
      Paper request.
    - Romer, D., 1986 (Box 2)
    - Rosenthal, H., 1987 (Box 2)
    - Roth, Alvin, 1989-1998 (Box 2)
      About exchanging papers and research data.
    - Rubinstein, Ariel, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
      Brief correspondence about bargaining games.
    - Runkle, Dave, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Samuelson, Larry, 1989-2000; 2 folders (Box 2)
      Includes discussion of proposed experiments.
    - Samuelson, Larry: Data Sent, 1996 (Box 14)
    - Samuelson, Larry Electronic Files, 1996; 21 files; approximately 2 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0001, Box 75, Disk RL11714-FL3-1173, Disk RL11714-FL3-1174, Disk RL11714-FL3-1175)
      Text files; zipped folders.
    - Sargent, T., 1987-1993 (Box 2)
      About exchanging papers and class notes.
    - Sastri, Tep, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Sauer, Christine, 1986-1993 (Box 2)
      Personal correspondence.
    - Sauer, S., 1988 (Box 2)
    - Saving, Thomas R., 1990-1991 (Box 2)
    - Schelling, T. C., 1987 (Box 2)
      About Van Huyck sending a paper to Schelling.
    - Scheinkman, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Schmidt, David, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Schotter, Andrew, 1988-1994 (Box 2)
    - Schulze, Bill, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Schwartz, Anna, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Scott Meredith Literary Agency, undated (Box 2)
      Publisher pamphlets and promotional material.
    - Sell, Jane, 1992-1994 (Box 2)
    - Selten, Reinhard, 1988-1994 (Box 2)
      About submission to International Journal of Game Theory.
    - Shapiro, Mathew, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Schleifer, Andrei, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
      About refereeing for Quarterly Journal of Economics.
    - Shughart II, William F., 1994 (Box 2)
    - Silvestre, Joaquim, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Sims, C., 1987 (Box 2)
    - Skinner, Jon, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Smith, Vernon, 1988-1996 (Box 2)
    - Snidal, Duncan, undated (Box 2)
    - Sobel, Joel, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Sopher, Barry, 1989-2002 (Box 2)
    - Stahl, Dale, 1989-1995 (Box 2)
    - Stahl, Dale, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Stein, Jeremy, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Stigler, George, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Straub, Paul, 1989-1991 (Box 2)
    - Sunder, Shyam, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Swan, P., 1985 (Box 2)
    - Sweeney, Richard, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
    - Tabillini, Guido, 1986-1993 (Box 2)
    - Taub, Bart, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
    - Taylor, John, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
      About submission to American Economic Review.
    - Thaler, Richard H., 1993 (Box 2)
    - Tietz, Reinhard, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Townsend, Robert, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
    - Tullock, Gordon, 1992 (Box 2)
    - University of California Los Angeles (UCLA), 1986-2000; 4 folders (Box 2)
      Personal correspondence and materials related to job offer.
    - University of Pittsburgh, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
    - University of Southern California, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Van Damme, Eric, 1992-1994 (Box 2)
    - Van Huyck, Alfred P., 1993 (Box 2)
    - Varian, Hal, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
    - Verkama, M., 1992 (Box 2)
    - Von Furstenberg, George, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Von Weizsacker, Robert, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Walker, James, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Walker, Mark, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Wallace, Neil, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Weber, Roberto, 1994 (Box 14)
    - Weber, Roberto Electronic Files, 1992-1993; 33 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0001, Box 66, Disk RL11714-FL3-0005)
    - Weesie, Jeroen, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Weg, E., 1992 (Box 2)
    - Weigelt, Keith, 1988-1992 (Box 2)
    - West, Ken, 1987 (Box 2)
    - White, Lawrence H., 1987 (Box 2)
    - Williams, Martin, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Wilson, John D., 1992 (Box 2)
    - Wohar, Mark, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Young, Peyton, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
    - Zeldes, S., 1987 (Box 2)
    - Zimmerman, Michael, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Zwick, R., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1986-1990
    Battalio's correspondence, which is about the exchange of papers, referee requests, and other routine matters. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1986-1988, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - 1988-1990, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Email Correspondence, 1993-2009
    Van Huyck's email correspondence from computer disk drives. Arranged alphabetically in folders that preserve their original order and title.
    - Email Correspondence Electronic Files, 1993-1994; 2,664 files; approximately 258 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0001)
      Text, spreadsheet, image, executable, and GIS files; zipped folders.
    - Es10users, 1997-1999; 10 files; approximately 22 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0001, Box 80, Disk RL11714-IHD-0001)
      Correspondents include Ray Battalio, David Cooper, John Kagel, Alvin Roth, Larry Samuelson, Vernon Smith, and family members, among others. Attachments include research material on experimental work with Battalio and others.
    - Es10users-mail, 1996-1997; 2 files; approximately 4 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0001, Box 80, Disk RL11714-IHD-0001)
      Correspondents include Ray Battalio, David Cheney, Drew Fundenberg, Charles Holt, David Levine, Thomas Palfrey, Alvin Roth, Larry Samuelson, and Reinhard Selten, among others. Attachments include some research material on experiments with Battalio and graduate students.
    - Eudora, 1997-2004; 2 files; approximately 13 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL11714-SET-0002, Box 80, Disk RL11714-IHD-0003)